▍2026 美网 女单第三轮
郑钦文 1-6 7-6³ 7-5 凯斯 · 赛后新闻发布会
Congratulations.
恭喜
Thank you.
谢谢
Epic comeback.
史诗级的逆转
Your thoughts?
你怎么看？
Yeah, it is a very very classic comeback.
是啊 这是一次非常经典的逆转
Especially I think the opponent
尤其是我觉得 对手
has a match point.
手里还握着赛点
That was also incredible performance
这对我来说 也是一场
for me.
难以置信的表现
Thank you.
谢谢
One question each, please.
请每人问一个问题
Howie?
豪伊？
I'm curious just what it was like for you
我很好奇 对你来说
in that atmosphere cuz Madison
那种氛围是什么感觉 因为凯斯
is obviously someone who's
显然是这里
a fan favorite around here,
很受球迷喜爱的球员
but you obviously
但你显然
had a tremendous amount of support there
也得到了大量的支持
and it didn't exactly feel like she had a
感觉她并没有
home court edge at all.
占到多少主场优势
And just what was it like playing
在那样的氛围里打球
in that atmosphere?
是什么感觉？
Well, you know,
嗯 你知道
she was really tough opponent.
她是个非常难缠的对手
I think she also got
我觉得她也有
a very very strong stroke.
非常强的击球
But actually for me, when the crowd
但其实对我来说 当观众
are supporting her, I feel also in the
在支持她的时候 我同时
same time they are supporting me cuz
也觉得他们在支持我
as more noise they got,
因为他们的声音越大
I feel like they are trying to wake me up.
我越觉得他们在把我叫醒
What I'm afraid is the crowd is so calm,
我怕的是全场特别安静
you know, nothing happen.
什么都没有发生
But once they start
但一旦他们开始
to supporting the opponent,
支持对手
actually I like those atmosphere.
其实我喜欢那种气氛
I like they supporting me also supporting
我喜欢他们支持我 也支持
the opponent.
对手
This makes me really awake.
这让我整个人清醒过来
Great.
很好
Congratulations to you, man.
恭喜你
You've had an up-and-down year,
你这一年起起伏伏
I guess.
我想
Did you feel when you came to New York
你来纽约的时候
that you were ready
有没有觉得已经准备好
for a performance like this and a run
打出这样的表现 走进
to the to the second week of the US Open?
美网的第二周？
Well,
嗯
when I decided not to play Cincinnati
当我决定不打辛辛那提
and make a block of training with my team,
和团队一起做一段集训
I accepted that actually I really needs
我接受了一件事 我真的需要
to play quality in US Open.
在美网打出质量
And then we've been working really hard
然后我们在美网之前
before US Open to to try
一直非常努力 想
to make a good result here.
在这里拿到好成绩
But actually I never think anything
但其实我从来没想过
about result cuz I just wants
结果 因为我只想
to fight every single match
拼下每一场球
and put the energy in each match and let's
把能量放进每一场 然后
see what's happen cuz I felt what's happen
看会发生什么
in the past three four months is first of all,
因为过去这三四个月
I don't have the right energy to play tennis
我没有打网球该有的那股劲
and then second, maybe my level
其次 可能我的水平
or my body shape wasn't enough good
或者身体状态 还不够好
to be in the top level, but after this block
站上最高的水平 但这段
of training, I felt really I come back stronger
集训之后 我回来得更强了
physically and also mentally.
身体和心理都是
Okay. Catherine.
好 凯瑟琳
Congratulations again.
再次恭喜
I just wanted given what you
我想问 基于你
were saying a couple of days ago
几天前说过的话
about how you you felt you'd forgotten how
你说你觉得自己忘了
to compete, that that was the element
该怎么竞技
of the game that took the longest
那是你花最久
to come back come back.
才找回来的那一部分
I just wondered the way you won today
我想知道 你今天这样赢下来
from being 5-0 and match point down,
从 5-0 落后 还面对赛点
I wonder
我想知道
if that gives you particular satisfaction given
这会不会让你特别满足 考虑到
the struggles you've
你在竞技状态上
had with those competitive feelings.
挣扎了这么久
Well, yes, like you said,
嗯 是 就像你说的那样
after coming back from injury,
伤病复出之后
it is true it's been a while I didn't compete,
我确实很久没有比赛了
so I felt I lost those energy,
所以我觉得自己丢了那股劲
I forgot how to compete.
忘了该怎么竞技
And then, you know,
然后 你知道
I play many matches here from the qualy.
我从资格赛开始打了很多场
I have lot of emotions
我有很多情绪
when I'm playing the qualy match.
在打资格赛的时候
I was even crying after I won
我赢下第三场
the third match reaching to the main draw.
进正赛之后 甚至哭了
And you know,
而你知道
main draw is just the beginning
正赛只是一个开始
where all the players starts.
所有人都从那里出发
Also, that's just my beginning before.
而那 只是我以前的起点
So, I fight
所以我拼了这么久
so hard just to start like everyone else.
只为了和别人站在同一个起点
And for me, that was really not easy.
对我来说 这真的不容易
And for today,
而今天
it's like after coming back from 0-5,
从 0-5 追回来之后
the first things in that moment I thought
那一刻我想的第一件事是
please I I I don't want be beaten like 6-0.
拜托 我不想被 6-0 打成这样
I just wants to win one game
我只想赢下一局
in that moment
在那个时刻
and after that the dynamic start to came
之后那股势头开始来了
and I felt better on court.
我在场上感觉好起来
I felt like I can see the tennis better
我觉得我能把球看得更清楚
and then I felt I have lot of energy
然后我觉得自己身上
on myself.
有很多能量
I can just keep pushing, keep fighting.
我可以一直推 一直拼
And at the end when I won the match,
最后赢下比赛的那一刻
it's like oof.
就像 呼
Wow, that's that's incredible.
哇 这太不可思议了
Finally, one time the luck is on my side
终于有一次 运气站在我这边
because all these three four months
因为这三四个月
have been suffering a lot.
我受了很多苦
Okay.
好
You just described how you felt
你刚描述了完成逆转之后
after you completed the comeback.
你的感受
Yeah.
是的
What do you think caused that comeback?
你觉得是什么造成了逆转？
What did you witness in Madison's game
你在凯斯的比赛里看到了什么
and what did you do in your game?
你自己又做了什么？
I think Madison has a really strong strike,
我觉得凯斯的击球非常强
especially in the forehand.
尤其是正手
She can hit the ball super hard
她能把球打得非常重
and super fast, which is I didn't met
非常快 这样的对手
those opponent before.
我之前没有遇到过
So, all the opponent I faced
我之前面对的所有对手
before, they didn't hit that hard as Maddie
都没有麦迪打得这么重
and they didn't serve good as Maddie.
发球也没有麦迪这么好
And I felt today in the beginning takes me
我觉得今天开场 我花了
a while to really realize, okay,
一会儿才真正意识到
this is the opponent I'm going to face,
我要面对的是这样一个对手
but luckily that I've been able
但幸运的是 我在第二盘
to change in the second set,
做出了调整
so I give myself more time on court,
我给自己在场上更多时间
trying to put more spin, trying
试着多加旋转 试着
to play more rallies cuz I realized once
多打回合 因为我意识到
the game start entering a long rally,
一旦进入长回合
can be benefit for me cuz my physique
对我有利 因为我的体能
was really good.
真的很好
I'm able to run everywhere on the court,
我能在场上到处跑
so I try to make the point longer.
所以我试着把每一分拖长
Yeah.
是的
But what did you see change
但当她大比分领先
in her when she had that big lead
眼看就要赢下这场球时
and was on the verge
你看到她身上
of winning this match?
有什么变化？
Well, first of all,
嗯 首先
I have to say she started her set really well.
我得说她那一盘开局非常好
I mean, I put a good first serve
我是说 我发出一记好的一发
in and then she hits the ball just right
然后她把球打得正好
to the corner.
落在角上
I felt in the first three I really couldn't
我觉得前三局
do anything.
我真的什么都做不了
I just did what I have to do, but she hit
我只做了我该做的事
incredible.
但她打得不可思议
And then suddenly,
然后突然之间
after I won the first game in the third set,
在我拿下决胜盘第一局之后
I see there's some like maybe doubt
我看到她身上有些犹豫
or I don't know, not as clean as before.
或者说 不像之前那么干净
She started to make a lot of mistake
她在那一刻开始
in that moment and I started to feel like,
出很多失误 我心里想
okay, I need to be there.
好 我得守在这里
I need to keep fighting, don't give up
我得继续拼 不要放弃
and let's see what's going to happen.
看看会发生什么
Okay. Eva.
好 伊娃
Congratulations, Qinwen.
恭喜 钦文
You talked about wanting to kind
你说过想要
of work on your physical conditioning,
加强身体训练
and this is a lot of matches.
而这是很多场比赛
How are you feeling physically now,
你现在身体感觉怎么样
and are you completely
你之前那场病
over over the sickness that you had?
完全好了吗？
Luckily, I think today and yesterday,
幸运的是 今天和昨天
I've been feeling much better compared
我感觉比之前好多了
to before cuz I remember
因为我记得那几场
those few matches, I'm not breathing well.
我在场上呼吸不畅
I felt a lot of times I couldn't breathe
很多时候我在场上
on court cuz my nose are blocked,
喘不上气 因为鼻子堵着
and my energy were really low.
我的能量非常低
So, yes, after finally after 8 9 days,
所以 终于在八九天之后
my sick was almost gone, and I'm able
病差不多好了 我能
to compete as my normal stage.
用正常状态去比赛
Okay. Last two.
好 最后两个
Go ahead. Go ahead.
请 请
just going to say, sorry. Harry,
我就说一句 抱歉 哈里
just with the number of matches
就是打了这么多场
that you played, tired,
累吗
feeling super energetic, feeling good?
还是很有劲 感觉好吗？
Mm.
嗯
No.
不
I'm not tired at all.
我一点都不累
I mean, if I'm not sick,
我是说 如果我没生病
I'm not supposed to be tired doing all
打这么多场比赛
those matches cuz honestly,
我不该累 因为说实话
the practice what I did in Bradenton,
我在布雷登顿做的训练
in Florida, that condition was super tough.
在佛罗里达 那个条件极其艰苦
Like every day when I finish practice,
每天训练结束的时候
I'm sweating from up to down like totally.
我从头到脚全部湿透
And I need to make couple of changes.
我得换好几套衣服
I don't even want
我甚至不想
to remember the practice I made before.
回想我之前做过的训练
Maybe that's because right now my fitness
也许正因为这样 我现在的体能
are much better, and I don't feel tired.
好得多 我不觉得累
Especially when you keep winning,
尤其是当你一直在赢
you just feel your mental is even more fresh
你会觉得精神比之前
than before.
还要清醒
Okay. Last two.
好 最后两个
I want and then wait.
我想问 然后等一下
Go first.
你先
Okay. Okay. Go ahead.
好 好 请
Hi. congratulations on the comeback.
你好 恭喜你完成逆转
I want to ask you
我想问你
about the 4-5 game in particular.
特别是 4-5 那一局
You were down love-15,
你 0-15 落后
and then a baby started crying,
然后有个婴儿哭了起来
and you had to pause your service motion.
你不得不中断发球动作
So, in in that moment,
在那个时刻
what were you feeling,
你的感觉是什么
and how did you get out of that one?
你是怎么走出来的？
Well, if it is a adult, probably,
嗯 如果是个成年人 我可能
I will look look at him very hard
会狠狠地瞪他一眼
or start to speak, but it's just a baby.
或者说点什么 但那只是个婴儿
I can't do anything, you know.
我什么都做不了
It's just a baby and that's that's can happen.
只是个婴儿 这种事会发生
In one match,
在一场比赛里
you have to accept the crowd.
你必须接受观众
Sometimes they're speaking loud,
有时候他们大声说话
sometimes they can shout you,
有时候他们会朝你喊
they can start to coaching you on court.
甚至在场边指导你怎么打
I mean, this situation it
我是说 这种情况
been happening like many times before.
之前已经发生过很多次
I think as a professional player,
我觉得作为职业球员
the really good ones, we need to be able
真正优秀的那些 我们需要
to handle those situations.
能处理好这些情况
Okay, last question in English.
好 最后一个英文问题
Yeah.
好
Congratulations.
恭喜
You played us a match
大约三年前
about 3 years ago against Bronzetti.
你打过一场对布龙泽蒂的球
That was up and down at the US Open
那场在美网起起伏伏
and you won.
你赢了
And we talked about whether
我们聊过
you actually like roller coasters,
你是不是真的喜欢过山车
the actual amusement park roller coaster.
游乐园里真的那种过山车
And you said you love it
你说你很喜欢
and you stay calm when it's
而且当过山车升到最高处
when the roller coaster is all the way up.
你反而很平静
How do you stay calm
在一场像过山车的比赛里
in a match that's like a roller coaster?
你怎么保持冷静？
And 3 years later,
三年之后
do you still like roller coasters?
你还喜欢过山车吗？
That's a very funny questions.
这个问题很有意思
First of all, I think nobody like roller coaster
首先 我觉得没有人喜欢
during a match.
比赛里坐过山车
I mean, if you can win 6-1, 6-2, 6-2, 6-3,
如果能 6-1 6-2 这样赢
that's the best.
那是最好的
But if the opponents are really good
但如果对手真的很强
or in that day you are not feeling good,
或者那天你状态不好
you have to fight the match
你就得在打得不好的时候
that you are not playing good.
把这场球拼下来
That's the case cuz in one Grand Slam,
就是这样 因为一项大满贯
I mean, it's 2 weeks
有两个星期
and you can't feel good every single day.
你不可能每天状态都好
And I felt especially today,
我觉得今天尤其如此
she Madison start the match very well.
凯斯这场开局非常好
And in one moment, I felt I'm only
有一刻 我觉得自己
in the defense position cuz she's
一直在防守 因为她
the one always attacking.
一直在进攻
But somehow, I mean, that's tennis.
但不知怎么 这就是网球
Tennis is sometimes feels like roller coaster.
网球有时候就像过山车
You see many times
你见过很多次
the people they have a match point,
有人手里握着赛点
but at the end we made a comeback.
但最后被逆转
Like today was just happening.
就像今天发生的这样
So, this gives me also a lesson
所以这也给了我一课
that in a tennis match you always
在一场网球比赛里
have to be there.
你必须一直在场上
It doesn't matter if you are winning
不管你是领先
or losing.
还是落后
You have a match point
不管你有没有
or you don't have a match point.
握着赛点
You just needs
你只需要
to be concentrate every single point as long
尽可能久地专注于
as you can.
每一分
Yeah.
是的